A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation records, officers' diaries, RG 12, A-E FA391
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Crowell, F. Elisabeth
  - 1927, Rockefeller Foundation; Crowell, F. Elizabeth; 168 pages (Box 84, Reel M Cro 1, Frame 20)
    On extended stays in various European countriesincluding Germany, France, Poland, Austria, and AustriaCrowell's diary entries record the interviews and conversations she had with nursing professionals, medical professionals, and RF fellows associating with nursing and/or public health. Topics discussed include country-specific public health programs; obstacles facing the development of public health nursing; the organization and training of international nursing schools; and logistics concerning the routine of RF international nursing fellows. (RF Paris Office)
  - 1928, Rockefeller Foundation; Crowell, F. Elizabeth; 233 pages (Reel M Cro 1, Frame 188, Box 84)
    Organized by interview or visit, Crowell's conversations address country-specific nursing conditions in Europe; nursing developments in Europe; the establishment and maintenance of European nursing schools and training centers; the placement of graduating nurses and RF fellows; proposals for RF funds needed to sponsor international programs and fellows; and requests for RF funds. Trips include visits to Warsaw, Budapest, Debreczen, Budapest, Krakow, Zagreb, and Venice. In each city Crowell assesses the progress of public health nursing programs and nursing education. (RF Paris Office)
    Public health nursing; Diaries; Nursing care plans; Nursing
  - 1929, Crowell, F. Elizabeth; Rockefeller Foundation; 195 pages (Reel M Cro 1, Frame 421, Box 84)
    While in the RF Paris office, Crowell's entries are organized by interview. Crowell speaks with professionals associated with public health nursing and her conversations address subjects such as RF fellows, nursing schools, training centers, health clinics, and the development of new European public health nursing programs. While on visits to European cities, Crowell's entires discuss the progress of RF programs in each city; the placement of nursing fellows from that particular country; development of new programs and new nursing educators; and the routine of RF nursing fellows stationed in each respective city. Cities visited include London, Vienna, Budapest, Prague, Skopje, Bucharest, Belgrade, Venice, Warsaw, Krakow, Ankara, and Dresden.
    Nursing; Diaries; Public health nursing; Nursing care plans
  - 1930, Rockefeller Foundation; Crowell, F. Elizabeth; 172 pages (Box 84, Reel M Cro 1, Frame 616)
    While in the RF Paris office, Crowell's entries are organized by interview. Crowell speaks with professionals associated with public health nursing and her conversations address subjects such as RF fellows, nursing schools, training centers, health clinics, and the development of new European public health nursing programs. While on visits to European cities, Crowell's entries discuss the progress of RF programs in each city; the placement of nursing fellows from that particular country; the development of new projects (in other European cities) along with new nursing educators; and the routine of RF nursing fellows stationed in each respective city. Cities visited include Prague, Vienna, Budapest, Zagreb, Rome, London, Lyons, Debrecen, Krakow, Warsaw, and Brussels. Extensive medical and public health surveys of Athens, Oslo, and Lillehammer are also included.
  - 1931, Crowell, F. Elizabeth; Rockefeller Foundation; 184 pages (Box 84, Reel M Cro 1, Frame 788)
    While in the RF Paris office, Crowell's entries are organized by interview. Crowell speaks with professionals associated with public health nursing and her conversations address subjects such as RF fellows, nursing schools, training centers, health clinics, and the development of new European public health nursing programs. While on visits to European cities, Crowell's entries discuss the progress of RF programs in each city; the placement of nursing fellows from that particular country; the development of new projects (in other European cities) along with new nursing educators; and the routine of RF nursing fellows stationed in each respective city. Cities visited include Vienna, Graz, Budapest, Debrecen, Sofia, Belgrade, Zagreb, London, Venice, Paraggi, Bucharest, Jassy, Cluj, Prague, and Skopje. Extensive medical and public health surveys of Spanish cities are included.
    Diaries; Nursing care plans; Public health nursing; Nursing
  - 1932, Crowell, F. Elizabeth; Rockefeller Foundation; 90 pages (Reel M Cro 1, Frame 973, Box 85)
    While in the RF Paris office, Crowell's entries are organized by interview and visit. Crowell speaks with professionals associated with public health nursing and her conversations address subjects such as RF fellows, nursing schools, training centers, health clinics, and the development of new European public health nursing programs. While on visits to European cities, Crowell's entries discuss the progress of RF programs in each city, the placement of nursing fellows from that particular country, the development of new projects (in other European cities) along with new nursing educators, and the routine of RF nursing fellows stationed in each respective city. Cities visited include Vienna, Graz, Budapest, Debrecen, Sofia, Belgrade, Zagreb, London, Venice, Paraggi, Bucharest, Jassy, Cluj, Prague, Madrid, Barcelona, Brussels, Venice, Debrecen and Skopje. Extensive medical and public health surveys of Spanish cities are included.
  - 1933, Rockefeller Foundation; Crowell, F. Elizabeth; 175 pages (Reel M Cro 2, Frame 1, Box 85)
    While in the RF Paris office, Crowell's entries are organized by interview. Crowell speaks with professionals associated with public health nursing and her conversations address subjects such as RF fellows, nursing schools, training centers, health clinics, and the progress of European public health nursing programs. While on visits to European cities, Crowell's entries discuss the progress of RF programs in each city; the placement of nursing fellows from that particular country; the development of new projects (in other European cities) along with new nursing educators; the routine of RF nursing fellows stationed in each respective city; and issues facing public health in each respective location. Cities visited include Brussels, Zagreb, Belgrade, Vienna, Warsaw, Krakow, Frankfurt, Prague, Budapest, Debrecen, Bucharest, Skopje, Venice, Madrid, London, Ankara and Istanbul. Extensive medical and public health surveys of Copenhagen and Stockholm (Scandinavian trip) are included.
    Nursing; Nursing care plans; Public health nursing; Diaries
  - 1934, Rockefeller Foundation; Crowell, F. Elizabeth; 175 pages (Reel M Cro 2, Frame 176, Box 85)
    While in the RF Paris office, Crowell's entries are organized by interview. Crowell speaks with professionals associated with public health nursing and her conversations address subjects such as RF fellows, nursing schools, training centers, health clinics, and the progress European public health nursing programs. While on visits to European cities, Crowell's entries discuss the progress of RF programs in each city; the placement of nursing fellows from that particular country; the development of new projects (in other European cities) along with new nursing educators; the routine of RF nursing fellows; and issues facing public health in each respective location. Cities visited include Zagreb, Belgrade, Skopje, Budapest, Debrecen, Prague, Krakow, Warsaw, Bilbao, Madrid, Barcelona, rome, Milan, Brussels, Sofia, Ankara, Bucharest, Athens, and Lyon. An extensive update on public health and nursing projects in Istanbul is included.
    Diaries; Nursing; Nursing care plans; Public health nursing
  - 1935, Crowell, F. Elizabeth; Rockefeller Foundation; 157 pages (Reel M Cro 2, Frame 340, Box 85)
    While in the RF Paris office, Crowell's entries are organized by interview. Crowell speaks with professionals associated with public health nursing and her conversations address subjects such as RF fellows, nursing schools, training centers, health clinics, and the progress of European public health nursing programs. While on visits to European cities, Crowell's entries discuss the progress of RF programs in each city; the placement of nursing fellows from that particular country; the development of new projects (in other European cities) along with new nursing educators; the routine of RF nursing fellows; and issues facing public health in each respective location. Cities visited include Ljubljana, Zagreb, Bucharest, Ankara, istanbul, Sofia, Budapest, Debrecen, Vienna, Warsaw, Prague, Berlin, Madrid, Lisbon, Rome, Lyon, Brussels and Athens.
  - 1936, Crowell, F. Elizabeth; Rockefeller Foundation; 155 pages (Box 85, Reel M Cro 2, Frame 497)
    While in the RF Paris office, Crowell's entries are organized by interview. Crowell speaks with professionals associated with public health nursing and her conversations address subjects such as RF fellows, nursing schools, training centers, health clinics, and the progress of European public health nursing programs. While on visits to European cities, Crowell's entries discuss the progress of RF programs in each city; the placement of nursing fellows from that particular country; the development of new projects (in other European cities) along with new nursing educators; the routine of RF nursing fellows; and issues facing public health in each respective location. Cities visited include Zegreb, Belgrade, Athens, Cluj, Bucharest, Istanbul, Ankara, Prague, Brussels, rome, Venice, Vienna, Lisbon, Madrid, Barcelona, London, Venice, and Lyon.
  - 1937, Rockefeller Foundation; Crowell, F. Elizabeth; 157 pages (Box 85, Reel M Cro 2, Frame 652)
    While in the RF Paris office, Crowell's entries are organized by interview. Crowell speaks with professionals associated with public health nursing and her conversations address subjects such as RF fellows, nursing schools, training centers, health clinics, and the progress of European public health nursing programs. While on visits to European cities, Crowell's entries discuss the progress of RF programs in each city; the placement of nursing fellows from that particular country; the development of new projects (in other European cities) along with new nursing educators; the routine of RF nursing fellows; and issues facing public health in each respective location. Cities visited include Tirana, Cyprus, Nicosia, Athens, Istanbul, Ankara, Brussels, Bucharest, Budapest, Prague, Zagreb, vienna, Lisbon, Warsaw, Krakow, Lyon, Copenhagen, Venice, and Rome.
  - 1938, Rockefeller Foundation; Crowell, F. Elizabeth; 125 pages (Box 85, Reel M Cro 2)
    Scope and Contents
    Crowell's entries discuss the progress of RF programs in each city; the placement of nursing fellows from that particular country; the development of new projects (in other European cities) along with new nursing educators; the routine of RF nursing fellows; and issues facing public health in each respective location.
  - 1939-1940, Rockefeller Foundation; Crowell, F. Elizabeth; 105 pages (Reel M Cro 2, Frame 810, Box 85)
    Given the escalating tensions in Central Europe, Crowell spends less time in the RF Paris Office this term. However, while on visits to other European cities, Crowell's entries discuss the progress of RF programs in each city; the placement of nursing fellows from that particular country; the development of new projects (in other European cities) along with new nursing educators; the routine of RF nursing fellows; and issues facing public health in each respective location. Cities visited include Zagreb, Bucharest, Budapest, Szeged, Prague, Lisbon, Stockholm, Copenhagen, London, Aarhus, Helsinki, Venice, Istanbul, Ankara, Athens, and Rome. Entries also describe Crowell's visit to the the U.S. and her impressions of various nursing programs underway in U.S. cities.
- Cummings, Ralph W., Jr.
  - 1972 July-August (Box 86)
  - 1972 July-December (Box 86)
  - 1973 (Box 86)
  - 1974 (Box 87)
  - 1975 (Box 87)
- Cummings, Ralph W., Sr.
  - 1957-1958 (Box 87)
  - 1959 (Box 88)
  - 1960-1961 (Box 88)
  - 1962-1966 (Box 88)
  - 1967 January-February (Box 89)
  - 1967 March-May (Box 89)
  - 1967 June-August (Box 89)
  - 1967 August (Box 89)
  - 1967 August-October (Box 89)
  - 1967 November-December (Box 89)
  - 1968 January-February (Box 89)
  - 1968 March-April (Box 89)
  - 1968 April-June (Box 90)
  - 1968 June-July (Box 90)
  - 1968 July-August (Box 90)
  - 1968 August (Box 90)
  - 1968 September (Box 90)
  - 1968 October-November (Box 90)
  - 1968 November-December (Box 90)
- D'Arms, Edward F.
  - 1947 (Box 90)
  - 1948 (Box 91)
  - 1949 January-June (Box 91)
  - 1949 July-December (Box 92)
  - 1950 January-June (Box 92)
  - 1950 July-December (Box 93)
  - 1952 January-June (Box 93)
  - 1952 July-December (Box 93)
  - 1953 January-June (Box 94)
  - 1953 July-December (Box 94)
  - 1954 January-June (Box 95)
  - 1954 July-December (Box 95)
  - 1955 January-June (Box 95)
  - 1955 July-December (Box 96)
  - 1956 January-June (Box 96)
  - 1956 July-December (Box 97)
  - 1957 January-June (Box 97)
- Dalakian, Michael J.
  - 1981-1983 (Box 98)
- Dalton, Peter R.
  - 1972-1974 (Box 98)
- Daniel, James Manley
  - 1964-1968 (Box 98)
  - 1969-1971 (Box 98)
- Davidson, Ralph K.
  - 1962 (Box 99)
  - 1963 (Box 99)
  - 1964 January-June (Box 100)
  - 1964 July-December (Box 100)
  - 1965 January-March (Box 101)
  - 1965 April-June (Box 101)
  - 1965 August-December (Box 102)
  - Diary Index, 1962-1965 (Box 102)
  - 1966 January-March (Box 102)
  - 1966 April-July (Box 103)
  - 1966 August-September (Box 103)
  - 1967 January-March (Box 104)
  - 1967 April-August (Box 104)
  - 1967 September-December (Box 105)
  - 1968 January-April (Box 105)
  - 1968 May-August (Box 106)
  - 1968 September-December (Box 106)
  - Index, 1962-1968 (Box 107)
  - 1969 January-April (Box 107)
  - 1969 May-August (Box 108)
  - 1969 September-December (Box 108)
  - 1970 January-April (Box 109)
  - 1970 May-October (Box 109)
  - 1970 October-December (Box 110)
  - 1971 January-August (Box 110)
  - 1971 September-December (Box 111)
  - 1972 January-March (Box 111)
  - 1972 April-August (Box 111)
  - 1972 September-December (Box 112)
  - 1973 January-April (Box 112)
  - 1973 May-August (Box 112)
  - 1973 September-December (Box 113)
  - 1974 January-March (Box 113)
  - 1974 April-May 17 (Box 113)
  - 1974 May 20-July 16 (Box 114)
  - 1974 July 17-December (Box 114)
  - 1975 January-August (Box 114)
- Davis, William A.
  - 1942-1943 (Box 115)
- Deane, Herbert A.
  - 1952-1953 (Box 115)
- DeVinney, Leland C.
  Leland C. DeVinney was a sociologist who worked for the Rockefeller Foundation for more than two decades. His time with the Foundation bridged two distinct periods in its history, as it moved from an academic structure focused on the advancement of knowledge, to an interdisciplinary approach devoted to the application of knowledge to specific problems. DeVinney's career reflected this change, as he moved from a Social Sciences program officer in the 1950s to the head of the Foundation's new Equal Opportunity initiative in 1963.
  DeVinney was born on May 14, 1906, in Gobleville, Michigan. He received his B.A. degree from Albion College (1931), his M.A. from the University of Wisconsin (1933), and Ph.D. in sociology from the University of Chicago (1941). He held a variety of jobs while in graduate school. From 1931-1932, he was Manager of the Fisk Jubilee Singers and Assistant to the President of Fisk University. The next two summers he worked for Depression-era relief programs, first as Assistant Director of Relief in Polk County, Wisconsin, and then as Assistant Director of the Federal Emergency Relief Administration's Chicago Regional Office. After earning his M.A. degree, DeVinney became a member of the social sciences faculty at the University of Chicago and taught sociology courses while pursuing his doctorate. Upon completion of his Ph.D., DeVinney was hired by the University of Wisconsin as an Associate Professor of Sociology.
  DeVinney's academic career was interrupted by World War II. He served in the U.S. Army, working his way up to become military chief of the Research Branch of the War Department's Information and Education Division. After the war, sociologist and Research Branch head Samuel Stouffer hired DeVinney to help publish the results of their wartime survey of American GIs. DeVinney coauthored Volume I of the resulting publication, Studies in Social Psychology in World War II, popularly known as The American Soldier (1949).
  In 1948, the Rockefeller Foundation hired DeVinney as Assistant Director of Social Sciences, with a focus on demographic work. In his early years with the Social Sciences Division, grantmaking--and indeed the Foundation itself--took a largely academic approach, focused on supporting research at institutions including the American Council of Learned Societies, the Social Science Research Council, and the Brookings Institution. When the Humanities and Social Sciences were joined into one division in 1962, DeVinney became Deputy Director and later Associate Director of the Humanities and Social Sciences. With the Foundation's reorganization in 1963 into interdisciplinary, "goal oriented programs," he was placed at the helm of the new Equal Opportunity Program. Under his direction, the program focused on training and developing minority leaders, strengthening Southern educational institutions for African Americans, and preparing African American college applicants. He continued this work until his retirement in June 1971.
  DeVinney died on November 27, 1998.
  - 1951, Rockefeller Foundation; DeVinney, Leland C.; 287 pages (Box 116, Reel M Dev 1, Frame 1)
    Organized according to interview and visit, DeVinney communicates with various professionals in the field of social sciences in the United States and abroad. He details the current projects, financial backings, study findings of interviewees and current methods of research. Progress of Rockefeller Foundation grants and potential future candidates are also documented. During his European tour he discusses issues of European research institutes during World War II in terms of funding, politics and Nazi influence. Issues of empirical research methods abroad are continually addressed. During his time in England and America, the diary is split into chapters regarding each university visited giving an overview of the university and then specifies research and professionals of the social sciences departments.
    Holland (Netherlands: Province); Norway; France; Germany; Switzerland; Diaries; United States; Social sciences; Sweden; Finland; England; Denmark
  - 1952, DeVinney, Leland C.; Rockefeller Foundation; 183 pages (Reel M Dev 1, Frame 293, Box 116)
    Organized according to interview and visit, DeVinney discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of social science. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, development of new projects and financing current and future research. A visit to the University of Puerto Rico is also documented to investigate making Puerto Rico a center point of applied social science research in the Caribbean.
    Diaries; International relations; Political science; Economics; Social sciences; United States; Puerto Rico; Rural population
  - 1953, DeVinney, Leland C.; Rockefeller Foundation; 236 pages (Reel M Dev 1, Frame 480, Box 116)
    Organized according to interview and visit, DeVinney discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of social science. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, development of new projects and financing current and future research. The institutions of focus for this diary are University of Chicago, Michigan University, Cornell University, Columbia University and Yale University. Topics of research include population studies, methodology, psychology and labor.
    Economics; Political science; International relations; United States; Social sciences; Diaries
  - 1954 January 4-June 30, Rockefeller Foundation; DeVinney, Leland C.; 171 pages (Box 116, Reel M Dev 1, Frame 720)
    Organized according to interview and visit, DeVinney discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of social science. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, development of new projects and financing current and future research.
    Economics; Political science; Diaries; International relations; United States; Social sciences
  - 1954 July 1-December 30, DeVinney, Leland C.; Rockefeller Foundation; 132 pages (Box 117, Reel M Dev 1, Frame 892)
    Organized according to interview and visit, DeVinney discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of social science. The interviews describe the background of the interviewee, their current research and Devinney's thoughts or actions on whether or not these proposals would be acceptable RF research grant projects. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, development of new projects and financing current and future research. Various interviews with professionals abroad copy the London and Paris Offices of the RF. The focus of the social science RF fellowships is to advance frontiers of knowledge in selected fields of special interest to the Foundation- notably international relations, economics and political science.
    Social sciences; United States; Diaries; Economics; Political science; International relations
  - Index, 1955; Rockefeller Foundation; DeVinney, Leland C.; 8 pages (Reel M Dev 1, Frame 1,024, Box 117)
    Index to the diary 1955. Organized by person, organization, or institution interviewed
    Economics; indexes (reference sources); International relations; Political science; Social sciences
  - 1955 January 4-May 31, Rockefeller Foundation; DeVinney, Leland C.; 155 pages (Reel M Dev 1, Frame 1,032, Box 117)
    Organized according to interview and visit, DeVinney discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of social science. The interviews describe the background of the interviewee, their current research and Devinney's thoughts or actions on whether or not these proposals would be acceptable RF research grant projects. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, development of new projects and financing current and future research. The focus of the social science RF fellowships is to advance frontiers of knowledge in selected fields of special interest to the Foundation- notably international relations, economics and political science.
    Economics; International cooperation; Political science; Social sciences; United States; Diaries
  - 1955 June 2-December 29, Rockefeller Foundation; DeVinney, Leland C.; 114 pages (Box 117, Reel M Dev 2, Frame 1)
    Diaries; United States; Economics; Political science; International relations; Social sciences
  - 1956 January 4-June 28, Rockefeller Foundation; DeVinney, Leland C.; 169 pages (Box 117, Reel M Dev 2, Frame 115)